hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and
i'm still i'm still wearing my dragon
head i'm still a proud dragon bro now i
started in the sahara conference room
here in our meeting room i was planning
on making my chair slightly bigger
because this is actually looking really
cool so i think i'm going to do another
layer and then i saw this
this this guy
reaching for the sky and it says stocked
observers lol
i could only assume that this is mumbo's
doing
is there anything in here at all
oh wait yeah mumbo he he made the
observers but he didn't stock it that's
actually a really good thing because
we have been entirely bought out
there's nothing in here at all today
which is why today's episode is going to
be a sahara mega stock we are going to
bring this place up to scratch me and
iskal have already partnered up iskel
and i have decided that we are going to
bring uh oh oh someone's got rid of this
already that must have been iskall he
told me he said he said to me green i'm
gonna i'm gonna destroy it
and we have planned to basically
bring idea
into bankruptcy by filling this chest
with so much stock that they will not
even be able to afford it now i i also
logged on today and i press tab and it
there's like one two three four
five people that are
on the dead team day of the dead
is it lads i kind of want to know what
they're up to that's a lot of dead
people
that are
i mean i haven't seen the server this
active in a long time they must be up to
something
oh i have nearly landed in this
twice
there's also an ominous lack of response
from the dead team
you know what we're gonna go and check
out what they're doing
i know where their bases i know what
they're doing they've revived the old
halloween district
well that could have gone badly now how
do i get to the halloween district
it's not labelled
i genuinely don't know which way it is
i have a feeling it's south
it's a great day to be dead oh they're
definitely up to something
where is this okay no this isn't it
wrong place this is stress's base i i
don't know where the halloween district
is
by the time i find them they could have
gone
no it's definitely not that one
that's the
halloween district woo
okay this is where i knew it was
somewhere it's so easy to get lost oh
that's a lot of trap
that's a lot of pressure plates
oh wait no whoa whoa whoa whoa we gotta
do this we gotta do this all sneaky like
if we wanna if we want to find out what
they're doing we need to go completely
invisible
[Music]
at least my name's not shown
where's the base wait what there's just
a flying house is this what they're
working on whoa
okay
that's probably that's probably their
base
that looks i mean okay if you take one
look at this thing that screams
you only have to take one look at this
place and it screams
the dead live here right
oh right over the phantom
oh this is this is really cool
i don't see them though though i might
be a little far away i don't see any
name tags either
can we sneak in i don't know what's
going on here it's not lit up either
it's not very deep like it looks really
big from the front so if i look at it
from here it looks massive look at the
size of it and then
it's like a really really skinny person
they turn sideways and boom they
disappear that's not very deep at all i
don't blame them because this has got to
be a massive project i don't see anyone
in there oh wait whoa whoa whoa whoa
excuse me uh okay so they are in there
they're just crouching
they're just crouching can i go and have
a quick look they can't see my name tag
so i don't even have to crouch
that was really stupid that was they
could trigger
they could trap anything and i it's like
i can't help myself the second that i
see anything that i can press pull open
i have to do it
oh whoa
whoa whoa whoa
yeah okay so they're up to something
they're definite they're definitely up
to something
and i've
been spotted oh my goodness
why is that this is terrifying
how are they doing these things
i don't like this i don't like this at
all okay all right all right dead fellas
you you you do you
they're not gonna hit me from there
ah they might
[Laughter]
just watch them face plant
okay okay okay okay they're diving
but they they're okay right right that's
that's definitely time to leave that is
definitely a sign that we should be
leaving right now
that was terror okay that's terrifying
um you know what we're never going back
there they can you they can do what they
like i'm gonna go back in my bunker
actually we can't go back in the bunker
because
we totally need to restock sahara
all right let's get on with the restock
then
so in order to restock sahara we're
about to do some absolute crazy stones
so here let me explain we need to fly
there is actually a reason why we're in
the nether we need to fly over
to
xi zuma void's
emerald shop because the reason is and
this is hilarious
x is actually going to help us restock
sahara
he is we are about to do some hardcore
economics this is how the world goes
around so i take a couple of shulker
boxes
and i buy all of the emerald blocks
and i do this with
my diamonds three stacks each
i fill up all of these shulker boxes
with as many emerald blocks as i can
carry
there we go we have bought out the
entire shop and it looks like we've
spent a lot of diamonds here but the
amount of stock that we'll be able to
get with these emeralds will mean that
it will cost them a lot more
this is gonna be so good so thank you x
you are going to fund the next round of
stock that you end up buying
so what we do is we take these emeralds
over to the villagers
and we release all of these there's
there's a lot of emeralds so this is
going to take me a long time to get
through but basically all i do is i
start trading up
and i will manage to get a lot of golden
carrots for one stack of emerald blocks
i'm turning my investment into major
major stocks
or stonks i don't mind and i can also
trade for other things like quartz
blocks
so we can stock loads and loads of stuff
based off of these emeralds alone the
only real downside is that it might take
a little while to get all of these
through but if they restock fast which
they are doing i can basically just keep
trading backwards and forwards
until i have plenty of golden carrots
now there's absolutely no way we're
going to be able to stock the whole of
sahara in one episode as
even just trading with villagers
endlessly will only stock two things
that we need in sahara
and there's a lot of grind to do so this
is only one small part of it all i've
traded with these guys so much they're
giving me better even better deals some
of them are only charging me two
two emeralds for golden carrots meaning
we're making even more money i can't sit
here and do this all day because i've
got to go and do some other things
but this is a good start and i can hand
all this over to iskall
to start putting in the machina because
i've i've been banned from touching
sahara okay i definitely i've definitely
had enough of trading for now we've got
to go and get some other things for our
restocking of sahara
so i've got myself some shulker boxes
and we need to head over to the nether
one of the big ingredients that we're
going to need for an awful lot of
crafting whether it's comparators or
repeaters or whatever it is we're gonna
need some quartz ore or whatever it's
called
so let's speed this up and turn it into
a bit of a time lapse
so as we fly through the nether
collecting all of the wonderful nether
quartz that we
really aren't going to end up using
because all we're going to be doing is
stocking sahara to make idea run out of
diamonds so i don't even think these are
going to end up being used which is a
real shame but what i really wanted to
talk about is the sahara merch oh my
goodness you guys are amazing you have
no idea loads of people have
legitimately
shopped at sahara and it it actually it
really warms my heart thank you so much
to everyone and anyone who's bought
something especially the limited edition
bumbo t-shirt
so
i just wanted to say while i've got your
attention that that the deadline for
international and eu deliveries in time
for christmas is actually on the 11th of
december maybe a day or two but if
basically if you want something for
christmas you need to order it soon and
then delivery within the uk is a little
bit later than that but if you do want
something from the shop the link will be
in the description and i can't thank you
enough anyway let's crack on
okay we're about an hour in and we've
got a couple of shulker boxes full of
quartz or i can't actually believe how
much i'd forgotten
how much of a pain it is the grind
hasn't been done for a long time almost
since like halfway to beginning of the
season just because there's actually so
much quartz in circulation it hasn't
been needed
yeah i forgot how painful this is well
anyway we need to head back to
anyway we need to head back to the broke
waters because i've actually got in
touch with falsimetry our newest bro and
i need to kind of show her the ropes and
show her the bro cave
hello falsima bro that's your name now
hello is that my name okay cool you are
officially a bro
and i thought i would give you sort of
the right of passage every time someone
is made a bro we we show them our bro
then our brokay for the dragon bros are
you in sweet yeah totally in like i've
had this head on me for a while now so
oh see i'm ready you get it you're right
you know what you know what being a bro
is about yeah
so you know uh this is this is the
entrance to the bro then but there's
there's a random book here that i
haven't actually seen the dead quarters
by tango i don't know if i should should
i read this now um uh it's up to you i
mean it's addressed to you so
nothing to do with me right uh green you
are invited to visit the dead quarters
if you are brave enough or foolish
enough the dead team would love for you
to visit the first floor of our halls
know that to enter our domain will
surely mean your doom
where we will welcome you into our ranks
right so they're just inviting to demise
me they just want to kill me that's what
i'm getting from here
feel free to bring a friend the more
souls offered the better our cause oh
does that mean me then
well i mean i do i think what we have to
ask ourselves in this situation is what
would a bro do hmm
maybe
to rub it in their faces it's pretty
brilliant it's pretty bro anyway let me
show you let me show you the
headquarters so you press this button
and then you walk down here
[Laughter]
false
it's safe i promise it's safe it was
safe
um someone's made a trap here but
they've got the timings all wrong
oh have they what what is it oh oh oh
that was a close one oh my goodness um
do you need some blocks that makes me
want to not go much further to be honest
with you oh that works dude
i don't know okay we should go ahead
with i'm going to actually drink a uh
fire resistance potion i always keep
some potions on me just in case i i
don't really want to go forward if
they've done that
so this is the bro then i'm gonna have
to give you a key
it does say architect bunker on it but
basically what you do is
okay it's fine it's fine okay
so what you do is you throw your bro key
in here you wait for the ding
and then you fall down no no no no no
that's not right is it no that's not
right
oh my
no
how close were you to death right there
you took so much damage
oh
no
oh my goodness
i think at the back of my mind i was
like they've definitely trapped this
place
but yeah um i wasn't expecting i was
like trying to fly i hit the bottom the
lava came out and i managed to fly out
oh my oh hold on
i don't think we can get to the bro cave
well this might break your uh entrance
but i do have water yeah go for it go
for it you sure yeah go for it go for it
this is
god we'll get rid of the string but
that's fine did that work
uh no just keep the water there keep the
water yeah yeah okay oh you're big
i can't actually see
broken it
i've got rid of the water
watch out this this is oh no no no
again
don't fall down
it's the second time
how there's a there's a sign there
there's a sign hold on
oh i see i won't touch the water then oh
my goodness that's sneaky that's ultra
sneaky oh my goodness okay can you put a
block there or hold on i'll wait for
this lava to there we go it's obsidian
now
then we come oh
no
this place is just trapped
galore okay i promise it's safe
okay should i leave the water here i
think yes people will just
the water column
oh they've removed the block and then
look what they did
oh there's tnt
here as well
oh man that goes down deep as well my
heart false my heart is going i
oh that's not normally what happens
right
no
no not too much for me to do every time
i think honestly i think if you weren't
here
i would have died three times over
oh my goodness hopefully
okay so this is the bro base it's safe
it's secure it's yeah it looks really
safe so far
i feel really calm
you feel calm i'm the guinea pig here i
was the one that went face first into
all of those
i'm pretending okay i'm totally
right so if if any this is the way into
the dragon bro den but if anything we've
learned that everything's trapped so i
have a feeling
[Music]
i think it's safe
i think it's safe oh look it might be
yeah
that
love so much
[Laughter]
i'm so i'm so paranoid don't stand in
the door
oh okay
right
this is this is the dragon bunker it
looks like this bit is safe yeah
and you know what
yeah that's that was it i was probably
the least bro that i was squealed like a
like a little pig there
it's okay i'll keep it between you and
me
don't tell the other bros okay i gotta
i'm gonna get my bronies back
you wanna do you wanna come and do this
thing with me the um the dead quarters
challenge i i guess so yeah she said
bring a friend and i feel like i feel
like we need to get one over them anyway
justified death three times i think we
might need to make a a a bunker bunker
to be safe
from our bank i think
you know what you need is like 10
different entrances and then just use a
different one each time yes
this one is like officially rigged and
not safe
all right let's go to the dead quarters
now it's like a warning sign i think
of course it's nighttime
i mean that's the only time to come to
the halloween yeah i think it's
permanently night here
look at that look how spooky this place
is and there's there's two mansions now
oh my goodness this is this has got scar
written all over it i have not actually
been here yet that looks incredible okay
so i think this one is the dead quarters
the one floating in the air
oh wow i think we're going to be
mega cautious
i think so
or do we go in like bros bro
i do it i do it
manage that
you got a bro
that's that's how you do that's how you
do you just got a bro are you going to
parkour you know you know come on a real
bro would parkour it i i won't parkour
come on a real
okay well that's not suspicious
oh look at my diamond sword at the end
of the tunnel
mysterious tunnel that leads to nowhere
yeah but look above you though
yeah
come on watch out
[Laughter]
you're standing right there
uh if i i'd turn back if i were you well
all right then okay so that's it did say
the first floor i believe yeah this is
the first floor okay um i don't i don't
want to move anywhere if i'm honest with
you
there's clearly more redstone there's
100 something behind the painting i
guarantee it oh you reckon
paintings do not get placed unless
there's a trap
i don't want it false do you want to be
a bro
i this is for you dude you got invited
here come on
all right hold on if i didn't if i drink
fire resistance then you'll be fine
right have a regeneration
be a bro
bro
i did it
that was a lot of potions can you see
the amount of particles
if you want to be a bro i can see the
string now go be a bro
wait where's the string it's all the way
down the end go on bro bro bro bro bro
bro bro bro
see it bro
okay okay okay
that's pretty bright okay so i think
there's redstone everywhere
yeah that's cool
oh oh
that hurt i don't even know what that
was
look at the amount of potion particles
this one this is behind the chest have
you opened all the chests
does that mean okay does that mean we
can take the diamond sword
come on you gotta be a pro
you want the diamond sword
i don't think it's i can't even take it
oh there we go
ah you can't think literally it's not
literally just a diamond sword huh bro
oh there's another room here
you literally
somehow false i'm not i'm not being
funny but somehow i'm literally just
running through everything you are
there's so many potions everywhere it's
just it's just because you've got to be
a bro if you hesitate that's how they
get you
i think this might actually be like
their storage chamber
oh
it looks like it actually
although is it no i reckon there's a lot
there's lava in the ceiling do you
reckon that's
we're just checking everything
i think we're good this is a troll room
i think oh wait that was a trap chest oh
that did something did you hear that did
you hear that
what was that i don't know again
no no nothing
that definitely did something
okay did we go the other way now i don't
really know what the point of this is
what do they want did they literally
just want to challenge us because they
thought we'd die
i think so sorry i put that there
she's scaring me don't
don't make noises right this one doesn't
look so friendly there's just darkness
at the end
i don't like this i think we're just
ruining their decor i think
it's all red herrings
why are you letting me lead
well you were invited i'm just here to
chuck blocks in the air and see if it
sets off anything
oh what's this
oh wow that's the halloween district
is there anything oh yeah i knew it
i knew it look at that
there's lava in there
oh in there
i didn't realize i was getting close i
was gonna jump in that and then i
thought hmm if i was someone else trying
to trap agree in what would i do and
yeah probably on the list
that's a good that's a good trap i'll
give them that that was good that was
that was close
but not today
i have actually got fire resistance so
in theory this shouldn't do anything
right you should be fine but it might go
down low we we've both got fire
resistance on right
yeah we have two minutes of fire
resistance if you if you want to be a
bro we jump in
we jump in okay
yeah i knew it i do it's not even deep
it's not even deep i just flew out there
that works
smoothly
smooth
i don't know i think they've tried
really hard they've maybe maybe they
tried too hard maybe well that's well
they're still in this doesn't look like
they're finished but i think this is the
most terrifying thing i've seen all day
what is going on in this room
you know what this is actually the most
terrifying thing i know they've just got
a dungeon with corrales in careless is
here guys
he looks like he hasn't eaten here you
go corrales
hungry he's hungry
are they are they starving you corrales
i think he might be next
he might he might be
that's who they're targeting next maybe
this is so weird i think we've bested
their floor
i think we might have unless there's
something else for us to do
is that it for real like but you know
what we got to do right we got to leave
signs
we got to leave loads of signs for this
yeah we're going to leave some signs
there we go we go we gotta we're going
to leave these everywhere lava trap
potions
i eat potions for breakfast bro
hmm i think that's literally it we got
yours
yeah is that the reward i think we did
it all i think that's literally it
i mean fair play to them but um we
as mumbo would say we live to live
another day
so that was actually super weird the
whole dead quarters thing
and
i'm actually quite scared that there's
been more traps up
look at this
green
[Music]
lecterns have
redstone
i don't know if that i don't know if
that's part of the piston system or if
that's you know what i'm going to play
it safe
i've moved over here so it can't do any
harm
grian you have mastered the first floor
of the dead quarters and unlock safe
passage to the second floor two more
floors remain before you win our
treasure
the location of all the traps on the you
could have told me this
before i went in the dead quarters i had
no idea why we were going there next
time two new souls must enter and the
traps and challenges will be different
and tough
you may let the next souls know
who's who's the next souls is who's is
it just some other bros uh we will be in
touch when it's ready good luck
suddenly
it all kind of makes sense now
they
i think maybe they didn't give me quite
enough information the first time around
so the dead quarters have a treasure
they have like a treasure room with all
of the traps on the server
and
if we want to get them we have to make
it through the floors so we just went in
not knowing anything and bossed it me
and false are true bros
and i think as
as we just nailed that we got to start a
bro chart
this is terrifying going through here
is it still yeah this is safe it's just
broken now it's just it's just full-on
broken yeah i think we're just gonna
leave it like that okay i think we're
good
man the paranoia is really starting to
settle in
so how do we display bro levels we need
we need some sort of chart here
that's gonna
show people how how bro we've been
ah
ah no
no
no what the heck happened there
what the heck
oh my goodness
that ain't bro
that's
seriously not bro
what even triggered that
ah
i'll see you in the next episode